uh so in the
angutu nikaya i think it's
a bikuni gotami she's asking the buddha
how do i know if something is dumber or
not dumber
and he gives you those eight
ways that you can figure out if if this
thing that is being taught or this thing that
that is being taught or this thing that
you are understanding is
in fact the dummy which things did he
give her
this would that leads to dispassion it
doesn't lead to passion
right right and so on so for just taking
passion for example yeah
the dhamma leads to non-anger well not
anger to passion to dispassion not to passion
to passion to dispassion not to passion
that's that's what i was saying in the
past when we spoke about it
the uh if it's not practical in the
sense of if it's not freeing you from
suffering if it's not freeing you from greed
if it's not freeing you from greed
aversion delusion it's not the dumber
that that's the criteria so if there is
no practical application of it
that it has a direct result in this
passion disenchantment it's not a dhamma even if
disenchantment it's not a dhamma even if
it's the dhamma you're reading
and talking about it and the suttas and
nothing else
so the difference is is um
the difference would be
determined then by the by the way you
took it
on that individual level personally
because you can have people dedicate
their whole life to dhamma
study of the dharma even understand the
dharma so to speak but it's all on the
level of ideas
which for somebody is the way to kind of
enter the proper practical application
of dhamma
but it's not necessarily guaranteed
because it can happen that you just stay
on the level of ideas
and then things can make sense
absolutely and you can you can connect
and and find connections in your ideas in
and find connections in your ideas in
all the suitors
but are these ideas when they're present
in my mind
when they endure in my mind as ideas are
they resulting
in me being unable to be compassionate
while those ideas are there
unable to be filled with ill will while
those ideas are there
unable to be distracted while those
ideas are there
and if if the answer to any of this is
no it's not the dhamma then
so that's the difference between like
knowing about the dhamma and knowing the
dhamma you can have an absolute fully
you can have an absolute fully
familiar uh expert pali scholar fluent
impali and everything and still be a
pathogenic not free from any of the fetches at all
not free from any of the fetches at all
no all the suit is by heart
now so that's that's that's the what i
mean but you need some knowledge
but knowledge starts on the level of
perceiving information and collecting
information so it's not knowledge in
itself
that which you perceive that information
that you gather that you remember now
will become knowledge if you start
applying it and if it starts having that
practical effect so if you you know if you think
effect so if you you know if you think
like oh i spend lots of time thinking
about dharma
yeah that's fine but now you want to see
are those thoughts while i'm thinking
about a dhamma
are they resulting in this passion while
they're there
or am i distracted on account of those
thoughts am i distracted on account of my super
am i distracted on account of my super
studies
do i get agitated on account of me
exploring these different views and so
on and trying to understand the students
if so means you're not taking it on that
practical level
so it's not the dumb which is
fine if you recognize it then you can
sort of start okay so let me learn how
to think without passion without greed
without aversion
then whatever i think will be the dhamma
because that's what determines whether
it's the dumb or not
not whether you're thinking and reciting
that which you read in the sutures
and repeating other words that's not
what makes dhamma dhamma
it's whether those phenomena when
they're present in your experience in
your mind
are preventing you
from from experiencing great diversion
delusion are they making a risen grey diversion
are they making a risen grey diversion
delusion decrease
and not a reason not to rise or they
don't make any difference to that
and and that's that's that's when it
comes down to it's on the level of the
view because many people would would believe
because many people would would believe
that
oh you know i'm thinking about the
dhamma i'm practicing the dhamma
but they would not necessarily see are
those very thoughts
are like are they serving as a
distraction as a
on the level of conviction on the level
of certain sort of um
like inspiration only or all those
thoughts really
while they're there making me
dispassionate and then even when i'm not there i'm
and then even when i'm not there i'm
this passionate account of those
thoughts that i had
or there is no such an effect or you
can't see it or you
you're still doubting it if any of this
is the case means it's not the dhamma
even if the dummy is all you think about
and and one way you can see whether
you know what you're talking about it if
what you're talking about is the dhamma
is through discussion with others
who have an opposing view because
so for example like internet forums or
sure one-on-one discussion you know
but if you are speaking about the dhamma
and someone criticizes that view
and you get angry yeah but that's
still fully convicted that there is a
conviction that you know that
yeah that should be the indicator that
yeah that is not what that's not the
time of the chat well that's not the
time even if the view that you've been
even if the view that you've been
talking about it
it's it's all based the suitors and so
on
you are not seeing it on the level of
this person which means it's not the
dumber for you
but you don't even need i mean that can
be helpful
but even if you don't actually talk to
others are engaging for them you can
just see it
on your individual level whereby engage
in some reflection kind of some suit
they're trying to understand
and then see afterwards when you sort of
get tired of it and so on are you calmer
or are you just distracted and tired
or are you brighter and sharper and full
of energy as a result of it
so what do you say are you agitated or
are you composed uh
israel any effort into investigating a
dhamma or
or dwelling in dhamma
should not at the the end of that when
you you should not be more liable to passion
you should not be more liable to passion
or your will
what leftover will be peace exactly
so you need to then that's women like
you need to learn then how to think
without greed without a version without
illusion whereby your own effort or inspiration
whereby your own effort or inspiration
will not induce those
and then you cannot get angry you cannot
get passionate on account of thinking
that the things that are the dharma because
the things that are the dharma because
literally any phenomena that arise in
your mind is drama
like that's what dhamma is understanding
of those things
understanding of this passion in regards
to saying that's the dhamma is the
practice
so instead of what you what you do if
you want to study
well like you study and stuff but as i
said you have to keep and keep an eye on
yourself in the process of doing so and not start
in the process of doing so and not start
sort of
if you feel you're getting fatigued and
lapsing and now you're doing it
mechanically stop you have to stop and regain the
stop you have to stop and regain the
composure because that's the foremost
you can't have too much of the composure
but also is it isn't it about
application applying what you are well that's yeah
applying what you are well that's yeah
that's what it's applied
you start applying it by not act by not
basically engaging in reading in
studying inspiration
that's fueled with craving anymore
because initially whatever you do
you crave towards it so to speak it's
underlined by craving
even your own thinking and that's why
you're not free from passion
but then you realize wait so i can think
these things
with craving but these things can also
be thought without creating
and that's what you start to learn so
that's what i mean you learn how to
think without greed without a version
without delusion
because the only time greed aversion
illusion arises when you lose
perspective basically when you lapse in terms of
basically when you lapse in terms of
your self-awareness
and get focused on the argument in point
that you were making even if it's with
the right argument
and for that reason that's not the
dhamma anymore
and that applies to like the broadest
sense to the most particular sort of you
know abu dhabi style discussion
abu dhabi style discussion
are you is this resulting in increasing
of passion or not
if so those ideas are not seen on the
level they should be seen
or those ideas are wrong one way or the
other dharma is only found on that personal
dharma is only found on that personal
level not on the level of forums and
others you cannot build it that's right
miracle of instruction that the buddha
would say so you teach dharma to
somebody and if they get to see that dhamma that
and if they get to see that dhamma that
you're seeing for yourself they get to
see for themselves
it's on the level of the miracle like
flying in the sky and touching the sun
and so on and he said that's the only
miracle he approves of
so if you do come across and say on the
phone somebody approves somebody
disapproves of your
of your view if you're getting
personally disturbed or defensive or
something means you haven't you are not
clear with your own view
you were presenting it already with a
preference with a bias
with underlying craving because if you
yourself were completely free from doubt in
were completely free from doubt in
regards to that view
there would be no room for passion
because there's no room for doubt no
room for real will
because there's no room for doubt and no
room for distraction because there's no
room for doubt
and then if somebody approves of that
view you will not be like yeah okay he
sees the same thing you wouldn't be
elated an account of it
if somebody disapproves you would just
the only thing that would reveal to
yourself is like to stop wasting your
time with that person
not like because you're offended it
seems like oh it's like like flogging a
dead horse
so it's just you try you try you get the
point across and they still don't accept
they still disagree with it they still
say you're wrong fine
no problem like as many times happened
in the suit as even to the buddha
himself when he would say something the person
when he would say something the person
would not didn't like what they hear
so they said no no i don't think that's
the case like it was the children wasn't
the children of the suffering the buddha
says and that man says no no i think you're
and that man says no no i think you're
wrong children are the happiness
and you know that's it he didn't want to
accept and it was okay so be it friend
oh i have to go yeah you go i'm not
gonna justify but or try to convince you
justify but or try to convince you
although you know the buddha knows he is
right and he knows why this guy's wrong
but he was obviously not willing to listen
he was obviously not willing to listen
so that's another thing if you stop
acting out of your passion
out of that sort of conviction or or
need to convince others
you will also get to see who could
actually hear what you have to say or
who wouldn't be having the right
attitude right from the start
because that's kind of obvious from the
beginning but people often don't see it
because they're already passionately
engaged with their view
so you don't actually have the
perspective to see who would hear you
who wouldn't
so then you're just flogging a dead
horse out of your own
craving and needs to be right or
something like that
but i think that's in the nutshell
that's the nature of the whole like
online forums that's exactly what
it always revolves around that because
most most often see you know it's not even
most often see you know it's not even
even from the start it's not the
platform is almost
at a disadvantage for learning because
everybody comes there thinking are we
all contributing to the same
no you either know or you don't know if
you know
you don't need other contribution if you
don't know
nothing you contribute is of value until
you know
so it's like blind leading the blind
arguing with the blind
because if they were to recognize the
right they wouldn't be on the phone
trying to like
chip in or get a bit from here be they
would be somewhere else
learning that which they don't know so
you might stumble upon useful
information in the forums
but don't expect a great sort of
learning insights because if they happen
it will happen in your own effort and
again not because somebody else who doesn't
not because somebody else who doesn't
know helped you that's impossible
and there's that other suitor you
mentioned i can't remember the
title where whereby
someone was disagreeing with the buddha
and over and over again and he said
over and over again and he said
isn't it wonderful how even though
you've been uh people disagreeing with
you you you're becoming even more bright
yeah yeah he was bright but he's
becoming even brighter and so yeah he
no he was disrespectful that person
he was on brahmin i think right he was
not approving what was saying he was
disrespectful interrupted him
like more and more but the more he was
doing that the brighter the calmer the
buddha was whereas other ascetics and
brahmanas who would be well there was one of
who would be well there was one of
that's another suit i think that's when
uh when the uh
that's like one of the criteria a lay
person should use to see whether
teaching is worth being followed or not
you find the teacher of that teaching
and when that teacher is cross-examined
and questioned
or disagreed with like is he getting
angry and wound up
if so you should not basically practice
what he preaches
right because passion aversion delusion
nothing he doesn't matter how lofty how
great how well thought his ideas are
look he's passionate on account of it
there is nothing worthy there to follow
me
so if if i come and question you now
like even disrespectfully
if you get angry on account of the ideas
i'm presenting to you
like you should be worried if you just
get annoyed with my root behavior
that's fine but they wouldn't give in
their eyes to anger or like like you
really oh you have to stop talking to me or
oh you have to stop talking to me or
something because you're furious now
which is what the buddha would often
caught in those like other
ascetics and brahmins would get angry we
get like how dare you question me
how dare you say that to me so you want
to see that for yourself this mean
you don't need to go and start arguing
with people just
as i said when you read other things
you're going to come across things that
that are opposing your view so
internally you want to see
is there still need in me for me to
defend my view or to prove that this is
wrong because i feel challenged simply by the
because i feel challenged simply by the
presence of opposing view
if so you are not free from doubt
and by the way this applies to any world
of view any worldly standpoint
regardless of what it is but when it
comes to dharma now it's even more
relevant that you are not free from
doubt then means it's not the dharma but when
then means it's not the dharma but when
it comes down to dhamma you cannot have
a valid dumb of you
and not being free from doubt in regard
to it at the same time
so that's the whole point when a
sodopanel becomes sort of he understands
that he understands
whole world thinks one way
against what the buddha said you would
know that the word was right because
that's what the dhamma is which you've
seen for yourself
so even if if the whole world says no
that's not the duke or something but if
you yourself are free from the dukkha
free from doubt in regard to in that
universal recognition of the certain
basically characteristics of the
experience it won't
waver you it will not perturb you it
will not disturb you you would just say
ah all these people are wrong
not i am right the dhamma is right the
principle is right
i'm partaking it because i understood it
but like
nothing to do with you and you would
know that which is why you cannot be
conceited on account of it
which is not fulfilled challenges or
feel challenged exactly
when you're self-centered you're
challenged but you need to defend it
that's what i would have said the one
who understood the dharma when they
teach they would
in the suttas like they would they would
basically they would not say
i know i see in that way but it's like
oh this is how i understood or this is
how it has been seen
because there's no need even if it's
factual yeah you did so for yourself
other people start with their conceit
which means if you approach
from that point of view even through a
habit not necessarily being conceited
they will take it wrongly so they won't
actually hear the dumb although they
could have heard it
but if you bypass yourself and just
present it in neutral terms the weight
has been understood
by you or whatever else if they get to
see the idea they'll see you right
but that's what i mean internally you
can already see that for yourself
on a daily basis when your views are
challenged what is the response in regard to it
what is the response in regard to it
internally is there like a rising
passion or fear of the challenge because
i might be wrong
all of that just outlines you what the
work still
is and you have to do it so with mundane
views for example uh you know political views
for example uh you know political views
well saying yes same abortion yes
abortion no
you're getting angry well if you're
getting angry means means like oh so
you're blind
you're passionately defending it if you
have fully understood
even a worldly view that is free from
contradiction clearly rationalized like you understood
clearly rationalized like you understood
it on irrational terms not emotional
terms because it pleases you
but because it's it's free of
contradiction then you would not be
disturbed even if people disagree
so if you are defending or getting angry
on account of your view
that it took means you took it
emotionally not rationally
you're not clear you're not free from
doubt so even yeah uh worldly views on on some
so even yeah uh worldly views on on some
like you know on some contentious issues
if you're getting wound up
means you are not clear about those
issues yourself
so you're just not overly compensating
with your emotional response of defense
you start it's built on an emotional
base every view will start on the emotional
every view will start on the emotional
base exactly but if you leave it there
that's when you'll be
well irrational
and the same it's irrational to get
angry on account of ideas of dhamma
because dhamma
and anger are incompatible so the fact
that you're getting angry because
somebody's disagreeing with your views
on dhamma or whatever else means you're
irrational which means that's not the dhamma
so whether it's whether it's a political
view or
whatever view on abortion or other
cultural aspects
are if you're getting emotional on
account of witnessing opposing views
means you are not clear about those
views yourself
so that should be instead of i must
conquer all these opposing views no i
must actually reevaluate my own views
and if i rationally arrive at the same
conclusion that i've sort of
gratuitously took through my emotion oh
that's great but then
you will be uh you will not be so easily
moved when those views are challenged
because you have clearly understood them
or certainly have greater clarity in
regard to them
you know what is right and it's got
nothing to do with you exactly you feel
it exactly it is
the way it is and so anyone challenging
you yes just basic rational thoughts that's
yes just basic rational thoughts that's
free of contradiction is your criteria
and you use that
and you come to a conclusion and then
you question that conclusion for
yourself and see if
it's contradiction proof and if so okay
now now if somebody presents you with a
new angle that made you think
instead of shutting down that new angle
because you don't you think further oh
thank you very much let me now
contemplate because you don't see that
person as
necessarily contradicting your you but
the this idea the idea yeah you see even if
this idea the idea yeah you see even if
that person
is attacking you you don't need to take
it personally that's the whole point
you look at the idea they're taking like
oh yeah they're ignorant in their
personal attack
but the point they're presenting
actually i haven't addressed in my own
thinking so i should not for the sake of shutting
so i should not for the sake of shutting
them up or having a good comeback
no for the sake of self clarity based on
ideas and values in regard to culture
and experience you are
it's it's quite important and usually
those people who do that were people who
people who do that were people who
qualify as wise men of
old who would not necessarily be
practicing the dhamma but they still had
wisdom in regard to life in regard to basically
in regard to life in regard to basically
things people go through
regardless of the culture regardless of
the period it's people actually who
invested time in their own thinking
not just because oh this is my view and
i will defend it blindly
like my religion or my identity my
nationality but because
no i reasoned it and this is the point
free from contradiction if you present
to me
something that i haven't addressed
haven't thought of that's even better
so in that sense so with the right
attitude discussion you can then learn from it
discussion you can then learn from it
but most people engage in discussion to
either convince or
kind of self-defend
you know by convincing you to agree with
me i kind of get validation of my own
views but again just ask yourself are
those views free from doubt
are those views um do i feel a need to
defend them
if so means i am emotionally bound with
those views which means i am irrational
if you want to get
if you want to be right or do you want
the right idea
yeah and then if you if you actually
invest the effort into the right idea
that will make you right
and you would not you wouldn't feel
conceited on account of being right
so that's that's the best kind of
discussion two people
are interested in the right idea yeah so
even though they don't have the right
ideas still
that well they meet halfway there's a
kind of yeah exactly
so both of them are willing to step
outside or at least step away from that
or at least step away from that
emotional basis of their view
and discuss terms on the level of idea
and that space that you create by
stepping out
just tiny bit might be enough actually
to reevaluate
and because emotional emotions are not
needed to hold the view at all they obscure
to hold the view at all they obscure
even the right view if you were to hold
it rightly
you won't be right because you're
emotional in regard to it
so you don't want to be emotional about
any of the views
whether it's worldly or on the level of
the dhamma so if you are
means you need more clarity whereby if
you develop it
there is no room for emotion to arise so
if somebody agrees with you you will not
be
over the moon or feel validated if
somebody disagrees with you you will not
be upset or
angry with them because you can separate
even if somebody misrepresents you you
won't be upset with it you try to
correct it but if they refuse and they
keep basically like saying but that you said
basically like saying but that you said
that but you didn't
oh you know he meant this but no you
didn't like when in the suttas out the
buddha meant
sensuality is not an obstacle it's like
oh don't represent the target of that's
a very bad camera
he's like no i'm not this is what he
said this is how i understood it
and on that occasion the buddha was able
to correct him but i'm sure there were
many cases when he could the people who
just obstinate
when they refused and they were okay
fine and just leave not talk to them
they're done
because there's nothing you would say
they would change that whatever you say
would just add to that
misrepresentation already because that's
often sometimes where people can feel
bound about
being misrepresented
i didn't really say that was like yeah
that's where the world is which is blind
leading the blind in every regard so
you shouldn't expect to be represented
correctly which means if you whether you're
which means if you whether you're
represented correctly or misrepresented
if you're emotionally disturbed on
account of it
you are in the wrong for that reason
so even if the whole world is
misrepresenting you the whole world is
against you the whole world
think your views are wrong you should
not be emotionally
perturbed on account of that and if your
view is right you will not be
emotionally perturbed on account of that
and if you develop that then you are
truly in a position to help others
nothing short of that
it's like a doctor who gives people
medicine to people just so they will
agree with him just so they will praise
him medicine might work or not but it's not
medicine might work or not but it's not
up to his knowledge isn't it it's just a
chance
or a doctor who truly knows what the
cause is
what the cure is he wouldn't care if the
med if the
patient says oh this medicine is better
and i hate you and so on
he still knows that's the factual
medicine and if that person refuses to
take it
he he won't lose any sleep why would he
but if he was doing it for the emotional
validation for his great ego because
he's the greatest doctor
means you're a bad doctor for that very
reason
you're not seeing problem clearly you're
taking it personally
and actually i think in the medical
field that's the whole point if a doctor
gets personally involved
he must be excused from the case
perspective goes
always even in mundane terms when that
happens so that's why that's why i was
saying that in slightly different
context but
that's what there is no if you do if you
start doing things on this level
there is no difference between like a
study of the dharma and the um formal like
of the dharma and the um formal like
practice and application of it
study becomes the practice practice
becomes the further study
the application now i started now i have
to go and apply
your study should be the application how
do you measure application
by basically anticipating of greater
version delusion and non-non-reasonably
diversion delusion
is less likely to arise if you engage in
these ideas and these thoughts
and maintain them in your mind
cultivating bhavana
cultivate certain perceptions you will
become imperviable to lust
and how do you know just think about yes
this is what a suba is and this is what
ugly is and this is the last of this
no no you need to cultivate it on the
level whereby it applies to you on that
practical level so there is no lust in
you and they cannot be lost
so if you start you will have to as i
said inevitably start on the level of
idea but then you want to see is this said
but then you want to see is this said
you want to find it here now
yeah well that's the thing first you
start but then yes you can you instead
of
oh let me let me kind of start on this
idea that i think i should start no just
rediscern the idea is already there
that's already the result of doing
things rightly
instead of me trying to kind of build up
these ideas so i can contemplate instead
i just recognize what's already there
and i see those ideas already around me
idea of ugly idea of death all these
contemplations because that's because it is already
because that's because it is already
there exactly so instead of doing it
under your own terms of thinking
you're just doing under the thumbs that
it's already presenting itself but
you're just ignoring it in the past
that's what i mean like even if you
practice mindfulness of the body even
that's an idea
in people's minds and you can okay
mindfulness of the body and having like
an image of your body and now you
and the moment you lose that image you
lost your mindfulness of the body
or instead oh mindfulness to the body is
the idea but instead of giving in to
pursuing that idea you go back to where
the body is
and rediscern the idea is already there
because whether you think about
mindfulness of the body or not look
the body is seated throughout all that
time hands are moving
i'm speaking all of this is already
enduring so that's what meant when i
said in the past
you find your body already doing things
there even when you don't intend
like it doesn't require your intention
to do it
in that direct sense but usually what
people see it's only that
that kind of um body that appears after
you intended to do things with the body
and that's what most people's meditation
becomes that overly controlling kind of
aspect of
i'm sitting i'm sitting i'm sitting i'm
intending to sit i mean
i'm moving i'm moving and you can't
sustain that because that's actually
secondary to the already living body
that does these things
so instead of you fabricating these
contemplations and
ideas the way you think you should be
practicing you need to
kind of refrain from that fabrication
and then see the body already doing that
and then discern
sitting walking talking as already there
done by the body in itself
that's why buddha said if when a monk
establishes his mind in first jhana
whether he sits walks extends his arm
goes to the toilet whatever he does is
done with full mindfulness and it's
divine in that state because he's not doing it
in that state because he's not doing it
he's just seeing it being done
because the mind has withdrawn from
greater version delusion
yeah effortless so same when you're
thinking oh i need to yo there's this
suit that made me think you're gonna go into
that made me think you're gonna go into
that abstract direction
but instead of that you sort of refrain
and then
find those ideas is already there and
during on the level of present enduring
body experience as a whole so try find those
experience as a whole so try find those
those
whether it's contemplation of death
whether it's body postures whether it's
thinking about base of nothingness
doesn't matter how defined how it is you
want to find it
as it is present experience enduring
on that practical level as i say not on
the on the level of these ideas which you
on the level of these ideas which you
might have to engage depending on you
know what you kind of um
certain inclinations are but if that's
all you engage with
you're not anything closer to
understanding in a way it could be worse as well
in a way it could be worse as well
because if you think those ideas
become the dharma you will then not be
seeking them on the practical level
yeah and then expect some some practical
results on account of you keeping those
ideas in your mind
now the only practical result is when
you practically start seeing them
and that's the cultivation that's the
exactly about maintaining it and
defining being presently enduring that's what it
being presently enduring that's what it
is discerning it is already there
not on your own terms the way you you
got these ideas and abstractions but in
the terms it's oh look
it doesn't feel right when i think of
the seated body it doesn't matter how it
feels is the body seated yes that's it that's
is the body seated yes that's it that's
your knowledge
you don't need to think of uni or let me
now practice seated meditation
you are already seated the phenomenon is
already enduring
the body is already doing the sitting so
don't lose the sight of that that is
your meditation regardless of how you
feel about
it and then all that
that sight of city body sitting there
implies all the other phenomena well everything
all the other phenomena well everything
else will come from it but
i don't want to give too much
information because people end up having
ideas about it instead of
no okay am i seated while i'm listening
to this talk yes i already know that
do i need to now oh i'm sitting i'm
sitting i'm sitting i'm sitting or
i'll think about no it's already there
so all i need to do is not completely
lose the sight of it
but it doesn't feel as as active as
satisfying as engaging when you actively
engage and try to figure things out
yeah it doesn't feel like that because
it doesn't have the craving
and your starting point is the point
with craving so craving will feel
more normal craving will feel more
palpable thinking with craving meditating with
thinking with craving meditating with
craving and so on now i am doing this
through my
craved determination but if you stop
using how you feel about it as a
criteria but instead
no the idea of seated body is still
there enduring and i don't need to
maintain it
and it displeases me because i'm not
doing it on my own terms that's fine
great now i have this pleasure to be
mindful of as in during their
not as my own doing
so you realize whether it's pleasant
feeling unpleasant feeling you will be
seeing it for what it is and during the
in your mind not being pulled by not
trying to
to get rid of it or or prolong it
and that's also it's going to become
apparent that most people's meditation
revolves simply around how they feel
so if you felt good meditation was good
if you didn't feel good meditation
wasn't good
but feeling should not be the criteria
for anything
at least of all for meditation but the
discernment well exactly the clarity the clarity in
well exactly the clarity the clarity in
regard to the enduring idea the clarity
in regard to the during experience
and the phenomenon
the clarity in regard to whatever
emotional current pressure you might be feeling